there may be occasions where you need to
send documents out the customers or
clients where they need to indicate a
preference for a specific item or there
may be multiple choice to do this within
word you have the Developer tab where
you can create checkboxes or drop-down
lists in this video I'm going to
demonstrate how you can add checkboxes
and drop-down lists to a pre-formatted
template you can download these
templates from the page on revision
Delon website so the first thing I need
to is I have my template looking on the
screen and I'm going to add some check
boxes alongside each of these options
the first thing I need to do is to make
sure that make fears that is placed at
the point where I want to insert the
drop-down list or checkboxes so I've
moved along there I want to use the tab
key just to move it along one further
wants to be as further and then I'm
going to go to the Developer tab and
what I'm on the Developer tab there are
a range of options now the tools that
we're looking for is in the control
section so if I click on the checkbox
content control and click that it will
insert a checkbox where the cursor is I
then need to duplicate that throw the
next checkbox and again use the tab key
to line them up just make sure they're
press the tab key to the lane double
down to the next option
use the tab key to the lane and look and
finally at the last check box now these
boxes should work straight away so you
should be able to check or uncheck these
boxes so a customer could then indicate
their preferences
however the document hasn't been
protected so customers or anyone can
actually edit the document which isn't
recommended so what we need to do to
avoid that is to actually protect the
document so if you look along the
toolbar you can see the restrict editing
icon and if I click on that it brings up
the range of options on the right-hand
pane so what I want to do is I want to
restrict the editing so yes it is
filling in forms who want to allow
customers
clients to fill in form so that's
correct and then select yes start
enforcing protection
so once I've checked that that left me
for a password and I will just enter
that password click look here so now
when I come to edit the document I can
check or uncheck the boxes but I will
not be able to edit or make any changes
no matter what a try I can't highlight
anything
the only editable options within the
document are other checkboxes